welcome back
today we are going to use the stuff we crafted last episode to get into the electric age
as per usual
we start with a steam turbine
which shall go in a room dedicated to the first three tiers of electric machines
we place our steam turbine
connect the steam pipe
and prepare a line of cables
we start our workshop with a wire mill
then we shall have a mixer
which will save us from having to deal with the crucible and the glass blow pipe
an assembler to save us from using the create assembly line
a polarizer to save redstone
a centrifuge that while using a lot of power
will easily extract resin from kapok wood
sparing us a lot of manual work
a chemical reactor with a fluid solidifier
to cheap out on rubber production
and before we decide what to do next
we realize we barely have the power to run one of those machines
so we channel all of our steam to our new bending machine
which will allow us to make rubber foils
with those we can indeed craft a pulley
which will allow us to extract infinite lava
to power our new big bronze boiler
with this simple trick that engineers do not want you to know
we have enough energy to run two blast furnaces
there is just one catch
we do not have two blast furnaces
not only we need more raw materials
we should also complete a bunch of quests that are in the way
and the main issue is that we are asked to make some batteries
usually the main annoyance is collecting the filling electrolyte
here it is managing the poisonous lead
to avoid getting our hands dirty
we craft an LV miner
which we shall power using water
or more precisely, high pressure steam solar boilers
and once those heated up
we started collecting some ores
we left the system run for a while
until we eventually managed to get lead
this is toxic stuff
so we want to handle it with care
we gently put it in our backpack
and then throw it inside our processing machines
we keep moving the hazard like that from machine to machine until we finally get the battery alloy
once we manage to turn it into plates
we have one more issue
we have to craft those into a battery
luckily, we can upgrade our backpack to have a crafting table inside it
which will allow us to craft the non toxic batteries inside the backpack
without letting any dangerous dust come out of it
but while that completed a task
we still haven't completed the whole quest
so we brace ourselves and take the poisonous material in our hands
that way, we completed the quest
and it looks like nothing else happened
the thing is probably that lead is toxic only when inhaled
unlike other stuff which will poison us on contact
but that doesn't mean we can fill our pockets with lead
it appears that in huge amounts it's still toxic
for scientific purposes and to answer the question someone asked for a friend
we figured out the maximum amount we can carry
is about many ingots and slightly more than half stack of raw mineral
but if we crush it in a more dusty form
we have issues starting from three crushed ores
and if we grind it down into dust
there's no way we won't inhale it
anyways, after getting our lithium battery
we move on with our progression
we craft an LV ore scanner
which will allow us to use hacks to easily find endgame materials
which we can't even process
once we find the stuff asked by the next quest
we lazily retrieve it
then, as suggested
we work it to obtain some aluminum
but while that was enough for completing the quest
it's an amount that is basically useless
considering our current situation
the best way to get more is to process some of the junk that our lead operation gathered
without crafting anything new
we indeed managed to double our stocks of aluminum
but to get even more
we can triple our yield with a thermal centrifuge
and while this gets (simplified?) by our new blast furnace
we go back to our thermal centrifuge to work some sphalerite to get gallium
this will be the easiest of the two components required for our next main objective
the second material required
is acquired by working our oldest nemesis, realgar
with the help of our backpack
we process it until we extract arsenic
and this was the other material we needed to mix up with gallium
that will yield gallium arsenide
to complete the quest
we have to take it in our hands
as a reward
our hunger bar is refilled
once we retrieve our stuff
we make smaller doses of that stuff
which we then input into an assembler
to improve the value of our efforts
we process some oil sands into polyethylene
which we finally add to the assembler to get diodes
and I forgot that sometimes completing quests doesn't refill our hunger bar
with those diodes
we make our first MV circuits
meanwhile, our EBF completed the other thing required for unlocking the MV tier
the first thing we do at this stage
is build a clay line to get infinite goodies for free
then we get the usual MV stuff
and a pyrolysis oven which we use to get activated carbon
that will allow us to get a gas mask filter to complete our hazmat suite
and with this equipment
we can now safely wash lead
and use it to learn how to juke
once we fully Learned how to carry lead
we use that to make some potin
which is great for cheap pipes
with those new pipes
we can hook up a second boiler to a second EBF
which we are going to run at HV power
so that we can melt kanthal
and this is going to be the material for the coils of our third EBF
which will allow us to melt silicon
with that, we can make transistors
and thus start our semiconductor industry
however, as soon as we got some new circuitry
we realized we don't even have the infrastructure to run two blast furnaces at the same time
so, before getting more energy hatches to fill the holes
we work on a better power generation setup
we now have a bigger main battery buffer
powered by an alternator
powered by a big crete boiler
fed by a robotic arm and a super fast pump
with that, we can now power our new HV machine array
and fix our EBF issues
with that, we are well set to grow our semiconductor industry
make more complex plastic
advanced chemistry
research into nuclear fusion
mess with living circuits
and build a ridiculously large battery
but I think our new refrigerator which can stock food for a lifetime is all we need
we take off our heavy work clothes
get a nice looking straw hat
and go relax with the nice breeze that blows on our crops
and this is where we shall say goodbye
欢迎回来
今天我们要用上一集做好的东西进入电气时代
一如往常
我们先从蒸汽轮机开始
它会放在一个专门容纳前三个等级电机的房间里
我们把蒸汽轮机放好
接上蒸汽管道
再铺好一排电缆
我们的车间先从拉丝机开始
然后再来一台搅拌机
这样我们就不用再折腾坩埚和吹管了
再来一台组装机，省得我们去用 Create 的装配线
再来一台极化器，省点红石
一台离心机，虽然耗电很多
却能轻松从木棉木中提取树脂
省去我们大量手工活
一台带流体凝固器的化学反应器
用来省着点做橡胶
在决定下一步之前
我们意识到自己几乎只够给其中一台机器供电
所以我们把所有蒸汽都引向新的弯折机
它能让我们做出橡胶箔
有了这个，我们确实就能做出滑轮
这会让我们提取无限岩浆
去给新的大型青铜锅炉供能
用上这个工程师们不想让你知道的简单技巧
我们就有足够的能量同时运行两座高炉
只不过有个问题
我们并没有两座高炉
我们不只需要更多原材料
还得完成一大堆挡路的任务
主要问题是，我们被要求做一些电池
通常最麻烦的是收集灌注电解液
这次麻烦在于要处理有毒的铅
为了不把手弄脏
我们做了一台 LV 采矿机
准备用水给它供能
更准确地说，是高压蒸汽太阳能锅炉
等它们升温之后
我们就开始采矿
先让系统跑上一会儿
直到最后挖到铅
这玩意儿有毒
所以得小心处理
我们把它轻轻放进背包里
再丢进加工机器里
我们就这样在各台机器之间来回转移这堆危险品，直到最终拿到电池合金
等它变成板材之后
我们又遇到一个问题
还得把这些板做成电池
好在我们可以把背包升级成内置工作台
这样就能直接在背包里做出无毒电池
还不会让任何危险粉尘跑出来
但虽然这样算完成了一个任务目标
整个任务还没做完
所以我们鼓起勇气，把这种有毒材料直接拿在手里
这样就把任务完成了
看起来什么都没发生
估计是铅只有被吸入才有毒
不像别的东西，接触就会让我们中毒
但这不代表我们可以把口袋塞满铅
看起来大量铅还是有毒的
为了科学，也为了回答某位“替朋友问问”的问题
我们算出了自己最多能携带多少
大概是很多锭，再加上略多于半组的原矿
但如果把它磨得更粉一点
只要三块碎矿就会开始出问题
要是再磨成粉
那就不可能不把它吸进去了
总之，拿到锂电池之后
我们继续推进
我们做了一台 LV 矿物扫描器
这能让我们靠作弊轻松找到终局材料
虽然我们连这些材料都处理不了
一旦找到下一步任务要求的东西
我们就懒洋洋地把它收回来
然后照提示
把它加工成一些铝
虽然这足够完成任务
但数量基本没什么用
以我们现在的处境来看
想多搞点，最好的办法就是把我们在铅作业中堆出来的垃圾再处理一遍
不用再造任何新东西
我们确实把铝库存翻了一倍
但要更多的话
我们可以用热离心机把产量再翻三倍
虽然这一步已经被新高炉部分简化了
我们还是回到热离心机，处理一些闪锌矿来提取镓
这将是下一项主要目标所需的两个材料里最容易得到的那个
第二种材料
来自我们最老的宿敌，雄黄
在背包的帮助下
我们一直加工它，直到提取出砷
这就是我们还需要和镓混合的另一种材料
混出来就能得到砷化镓
要完成任务
我们得把它拿在手里
作为奖励
我们的饥饿条被回满了
取回东西之后
我们把这种材料分装成更小的剂量
然后送进组装机里
让我们的努力更值钱
我们把一些油砂加工成聚乙烯
最后再把它丢进组装机，做出二极管
我忘了，有时候完成任务并不会回满我们的饥饿条
有了这些二极管
我们做出了第一批 MV 电路
与此同时，我们的 EBF 也完成了解锁 MV 等级所需的另一项工作
这个阶段我们先做的第一件事
就是搭一条黏土生产线，白嫖无限好东西
然后再补齐常规的 MV 设施
再加上一台热解炉，用来做活性炭
这样就能做出防毒面具滤芯，补齐我们的防化套装
有了这套装备
我们现在可以安全地处理铅了
还能用它来学会怎么走位
一旦我们真正学会怎么带着铅行动
就可以用它来做一些白镴
这东西特别适合做便宜管道
有了这些新管道
我们就能把第二座锅炉接到第二台 EBF 上
我们会用 HV 电压去驱动它
好把坎塔尔熔掉
这将成为第三台 EBF 线圈的材料
有了它，我们就能熔化硅
这样就能制造晶体管
从而启动我们的半导体产业
但刚拿到新电路不久
我们就意识到自己甚至没有足够的基础设施，同时运行两座高炉
所以在补更多能量仓之前
我们先把精力放在更好的供电方案上
现在我们有了更大的主电池缓冲
由交流发电机供电
而交流发电机又由一座大型混凝土锅炉驱动
这锅炉则由机械臂和超高速泵供料
有了这套系统，我们现在可以给新的 HV 机器阵列供电
也能解决 EBF 的供电问题
这样一来，我们就能稳稳地发展半导体产业
做更复杂的塑料
推进高级化学
研究核聚变
折腾活体电路
还造一块大得离谱的电池
但我觉得，能存上一辈子食物的新冰箱就已经够用了
我们脱下厚重的工作服
戴上一顶好看的草帽
去享受吹过庄稼的微风
这就是我们该说再见的时候